jp3476
COMS3102-HW1

cat myhw1text

[2016-09-14 11:32.45]  ~
[Jason.Catalina] ➤ ssh jp3476@104.196.122.167
X11 forwarding request failed on channel 0
Last login: Wed Sep 14 01:44:54 2016 from dyn-160-39-141-67.dyn.columbia.edu
[jp3476@coms3102server ~]$ ls
hw1
[jp3476@coms3102server ~]$ cd hw1
[jp3476@coms3102server hw1]$ ls
myhw1src  myhw1text.txt
[jp3476@coms3102server hw1]$ cat myhw1text.txt
1. Wow, it's been a while since I was asked about my first computer.
When I was about 6 years old, my parents bought a used Dell desktop,
one of the early 2000 models (it was 2002 at the time) and it was
absolutely fantastic. From the moment I learned that you could play
free games using a mouse and keyboard I was hooked. The only thing
I didn't like about it was the annoyingly slow dial up connection
that was standard back in those dark ages.

2. My experience with Linux is a little tricky, I first downloaded
and installed Ubuntu on a spare Chromebook for kicks. However, it
only lasted a few weeks since I got tired of resetting my Chromebook
in order to log into the Ubuntu operating system. Much of what I remember
is using terminal commands to download and install updates. It was
fun but I never went any deeper than that.

3. I would really love to learn more about Linux and its capabilities
as a tool for programmers. Linux appears to be very versatile and
capable in handling almost any kind of task, whether it be complex
or very simple. It would be really nice if I could learn Linux at
a somewhat relaxed pace since I am currently taking 6 other classes
but I can only hope.

4. What I would I like to learn in 3102 is to know and understand
how to navigate the terminal like a pro and be equipped to utilize
all the software and programs that are usable only on Linux. Practicality
is what I aim to get out of this course. Theory is only useful for me
in a few cases which is why I prefer to run simulations and tests
on a computer instead of proving theorems and axioms.

cat myhw1src

[jp3476@coms3102server hw1]$
[jp3476@coms3102server hw1]$ cat myhw1src
id
hostname
uptime
[jp3476@coms3102server hw1]$

source myhw1src

[jp3476@coms3102server hw1]$ source myhw1src
uid=525(jp3476) gid=526(jp3476) groups=526(jp3476) context=unconfined_u:unconfined_r:unconfined_t:s0-s0:c0.c1023
coms3102server
 11:34:56 up 7 days, 23:29,  4 users,  load average: 0.00, 0.00, 0.00
[jp3476@coms3102server hw1]$


6th 'echo'
Echo the STRING(s) to standard output.

About our server
1. Distribution is version 6.8.

2. Home directory is /home/jp3476.

3. Hostname is coms3102server.

4. uid=525(jp3476)

5. gid=526(jp3476)

6. Wed Sep 14 01:14:15 EDT 2016

7.  01:16:35 up 7 days, 13:11,  6 users,  load average: 0.00, 0.00, 0.00
